The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Now,
take me to the Mysterious Yin Cauldron.
Naturally...
Ta Shan,
Upper Celestial has already shown you mercy.
Don't be so ungrateful.
Grandpa,
no one knows the Mysterious Yin Cauldron's location better than me.
You're getting old.
As the altar's guardian,
it's my duty to lead the way.
The name "Chosen Immortal Clan"
is because we were chosen by Celestials
and blessed by their grace.
We must guard this place
and protect the Mysterious Yin Cauldron until the Celestials return.
This is the mission the Celestials gave us.
Every member of the Chosen Immortal Clan
should take pride in this.
Is that a Celestial ?
Move a little bit,
I want to see too.
When I was their age,
I believed those stories too.
Altar
Chosen Immortal Clan
So I cultivated day and night,
I never dared to slack off,
and I became my generation's guardian of the altar.
Chosen Immortal Clan...
Forsaken Immortal Clan...
Their name is almost the same.
What's the link between them ?
The Mysterious Yin Cauldron is at the bottom of the cave.
Senior,
please.
Do you have something to ask ?
Senior,
are you...
really a Celestial ?
I'm not.
I knew it...
If you suspected me,
why did you bring me in here ?
The person who saved our clan
was you,
not that non-existent Celestial.
Although the Celestial Realm has collapsed,
some Celestials might have survived.
Even if some did,
I'm afraid they abandoned us long ago.
What "chosen by Celestials"
and "blessed by their grace"...
Senior, do you know why
this place is overrun with fog beasts ?
The Clan Head certainly never told you.
These fog beasts
originated from the Mysterious Yin Cauldron itself !
Mysterious Yin Cauldron
That's right.
Ironic, isn't it ?
What our clan protects
is precisely the source of the fog beasts slaughtering our people.
A single word from a Celestial
made us protect it for 30 000 years !
And the result ?
How many of our members
haven't lost one of their limbs ?
Grandpa always talks of loyalty and righteousness,
but are loyalty and righteousness
worth the lives of the entire clan !?
Senior,
Ta Shan has a request.
Now that the clan
sees Senior as a Celestial,
no one will disobey
whatever you say.
Junior begs Senior
to lead us away from this place
by using your identity as a Celestial.
If you agree,
Ta Shan will serve you for life,
without regard for life or death.
I was also accidentally transported here
and I don't know where the exit is.
Even Senior doesn't know...
I led exploration teams several times.
Following the rifts
only led to another dead zone.
This place is surrounded in fleshy walls
and has no sky.
Even if we force our way through,
there is only endless void.
Surronded in fleshy walls...
Endless void outside...
The Celestial Realm has always had a tradition of capturing beasts,
they specialized in rare beasts.
This beast
hides in dark, mysterious places.
Its belly can contain a world.
Its name is
the Nether Beast.
This beast's body forms its own formation of restrictions
with netherworld fog as its source.
Where the fog rises
is the formation's eye.
To leave this formation,
the formation's eye must be broken.
What is that ?
Cauldron Spirit
Mysterious Yin Cauldron
This sound attacks the Origin Soul directly.
Teleport...
A teleportation formation !
The exit is hidden beneath the cauldron !
Upper Celestial !
Ta Shan,
what did you do !?
How did you provoke the Cauldron Spirit's wrath ?
Cauldron Spirit ?
Grandpa,
there's a teleportation formation beneath the cauldron.
We just saw it with our own eyes !
Wh...What  ?
Impossible.
None of our ancestors ever mentioned it.
But we really saw it !
That must be the exit !
Exit ?
The exit to leave this place !?
Silence !
Our clan was ordered to protect this cauldron.
How dare you harbor thoughts of deserting our duty ?
While the cauldron stands,
our clan also stands.
Grandpa !
Being forced to kneel for so long
made him servile.
Even if the others wish to help,
if he isn't willing,
it will all be in vain.
You may withdraw,
I will enter seclusion here.
Understood.
This place
shall become a forbidden area.
No one will be allowed to disturb Upper Celestial.
I can't stay here long.
The spell that Cauldron Spirit used attacks the Origin Soul.
It seems I need to find a way to protect my Origin Soul
before going back in.
I gained quite a lot from the Thunder Celestial Realm.
There might be
a solution among the loot.
I need to refine an artifact here
so the three of you will guard me.
100 zhang in all directions,
don't let anyone step in.
Master can rest assured.
Little Xu will protect you to the death.
Whoever comes to disturb your cultivation
will have to first step upon my corpse.
I, Xu Liguo, live a life of loyalty and righteousness !
You two,
come with me.
To guard Master,
you must stand your ground.
Just because I stopped flattering him a bit,
and I've already fallen out of favor.
It seems I still need more practice !
I, Xu Liguo,
was born to live a life of loyalty
and to fight for righteousness !
This heart, this body,
the heavens and the earth can bear witness !
The Collection Pavilion
was my greatest harvest from the Thunder Celestial Realm.
A nine-story pagoda...
How many celestial spells does it contain ?
Unfortunately, the restrictions are hard to break.
I must leave it for later.
This item is extraordinary,
I'll hide it like this
just to be safe.
The Ancient God Leather Armor...
Maybe I can attach it to my Origin Soul.
Like this,
that Cauldron Spirit can no longer harm me.
This talisman is no ordinary item.
Perhaps I can ask that person from the Thunder Celestial Temple.
What is this ?
This...
This is...
Fellow cultivator...
Senior ! Spare my life !
I have treasures,
I'll give them all to you !
You're just an Origin Soul.
How could you have treasures ?
I...
I have some !
You took my bag of holding
but there's a hidden compartment inside
with a restriction !
I'm the only one that can open it !
A defensive artifact ?
It's usable.
What else ?
There's more...
There's more !
My golden lock !
An ordinary item
isn't enough to buy your life.
No...
No !
I still have some !
I...
Right,
an Allheaven Stone !
I know you can obtain an Allheaven Stone !
If you spare me,
I'll lead you there !
An Allheaven Stone...
A rune ?
I wonder what effect it has.
Mosquito Beast,
come.
A sealing effect ?
This is the true valuable part of his artifact.
The messenger that carried the golden lock
truly wasted its potential.
If I could take this rune
and draw a lot of it on an artifact...
In that case,
I shall use this sealing rune
to bestow my stamp with a spell !
8 days later
This stamp
shall be named the Celestial Sealing Stamp.
With this stamp,
I'll be able to deal with the Cauldron Spirit.
The Celestials ordered them to guard the cauldron,
but allowed the fog beasts to slaughter them.
All of this
feels like a part of a bigger scheme.
If there really is a Celestial manipulating everything behind the scenes,
no matter what he wants to do,
I'll need enough power
to break out of here.
If he's still there,
I might have to fight.
I need one thing
to slay a Celestial.
At Early stage Soul Formation,
by wielding the first God Slaying Chariot,
I could kill Late stage Soul Formation cultivators.
At Soul Transformation,
with the might of the second God Slaying Chariot,
I could challenge Early stage Ascendant cultivators.
At Ascendant,
by releasing seals of the second God Slaying Chariot,
I was able to fight Illusory Yin cultivators.
I wonder what this third God Slaying Chariot
has in store for me.
The third God Slaying Chariot I forged
is far more powerful
than I had expected.
If all its seals are released,
it would make slaying Celestials or Gods,
a trivial matter.
Hundreds of years have passed in the blink of an eye.
Before, to break a seal,
I had to use all my strength.
But...
not anymore.
Goodness,
the fiend's commotion is truly terrifying.
This...
What...
What's happening ?
No bystanders allowed !
My master is in seclusion.
I, Xu Liguo, am utterly loyal.
Those who dare to take a step
will have to step over my corpse !
Such a loyal servant !
We admire your loyalty.
So he is loyal to Senior...
Compared to our clan,
his fate is far more fortunate.
God Slaying Chariot,
open the seal !
What kind of monster is this ?
Oh, heavens !
Mosquito Beast, Thunder Toad,
you hold it first !
To subdue this beast,
it must be linked to one's life
by refining the God Slaying Chariot into a Life Artifact.
If the chariot survives, the person survives.
If the chariot is destroyed, the person perishes.
But if it's not refined as a Life Artifact,
the 7 seals
can be transformed into 7 collapse spells.
If it submits within 7 strikes,
it can be used.
In case of failure,
the beast soul's backlash
will bring certain death.
I'll make you
submit to me in 7 strikes !
Collapse !
Kneel !
Upper Celestial's spells are truly extraordinary !
Indeed !
That's right,
he's truly amazing !
That was a big enough commotion.
If there really is a Celestial,
he should have appeared by now.
Butterfly
Beast soul
Third God Slaying Chariot
The third God Slaying Chariot...
Why is it
a butterfly ?
Lowly servant of this realm,
why are you causing trouble ?
Ask
Qi Condensation
the perilous path filled with countless blades.
Foundation Establishment
Can the mundane world be shattered
Core Formation
by a child's steadfast heart ?
Nascent Soul
If the laws of this world
Soul Formation
stand in the way,
Soul Transformation
I'll defy the universe to tread the heavens
and ask this question to the sky.
Ascendant
My heart's deepest wish
is to not kneel before these mountains and rivers.
Don't accept your doomed fate,
karma can be changed.
Unwilling to let go,
my obsessions propel me forward.
Don't be afraid.
Thunder rumbles as I dare to tread through the reincarnation cycle.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.